<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>management on Charlton Austin</title>
    <link>https://charltonaustin.com/categories/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in management on Charlton Austin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charltonaustin.com/categories/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Communication in Remote Start-Ups</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/communication-in-remote-start-ups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/communication-in-remote-start-ups/</guid>
      <description>Communication Challenges in a Remote Startup: Tips for Overcoming Them Remote work has become increasingly popular in recent years, but it comes with its own unique set of challenges One of the biggest hurdles that remote startups face is communication In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some of the common communication challenges in a remote startup and provide tips for overcoming them.
1. Work on Communication Skills Communication is always more difficult in a remote environment However, there are things you can do to combat this While many people may suggest adding more meetings, this can actually kill productivity Instead, focus on making sure your team knows and learns strong communication skills This means respecting other people&amp;rsquo;s opinions, avoiding arguments, and taking on disagreements in a tactful manner This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should hide disagreements, but rather that you should approach them constructively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Productive Weekly One-on-One Meetings with Employees</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-weekly-one-on-one-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-weekly-one-on-one-checklist/</guid>
      <description>As a manager, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to have regular one-on-one meetings with your direct reports. These meetings allow you to stay connected with your employees, address their concerns, and give them the feedback they need to grow professionally. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll share a simple checklist to help you have effective weekly check-ins with your employees.
The Checklist: How was last week? Is there anything I need to know about that I don&amp;rsquo;t know about?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pomodoro Method Follow Up</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/pomodoro-method-follow-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 07:00:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/pomodoro-method-follow-up/</guid>
      <description>Pomodoro Technique I&amp;rsquo;ve blogged about it before. Recently I dusted off my old method and tried to implement it. I found that there were some rather strange problems with my old method and MacOS. So I wanted to help some people.
The scripts We have a few scripts. We have a delayed_mac script. This script just takes a command and a time in mins. It executes the command that many mins later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bugs In Software</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/bugs-in-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/bugs-in-software/</guid>
      <description>The Architecture of Open Source Applications If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen or read The Architecture of Open Source Applications then you are missing out. Sure, it is a bit long. Also, each section is written by a different writer making it slightly inconsistent. But, there are gems throughout the book that make it worth the read.
One of the gems Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of one of the gems from the Berkeley DB section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blameless Postmortems</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/blameless-postmortems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/blameless-postmortems/</guid>
      <description>Subject Why should we have blameless postmortems?
Context I recently read a blog post about blameless postmortems from Etsy. In it there was a simple question about why software engineers shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be punished:
Why shouldn’t they be punished or reprimanded? Because an engineer who thinks they’re going to be reprimanded are disincentivized to give the details necessary to get an understanding of the mechanism, pathology, and operation of the failure. This lack of understanding of how the accident occurred all but guarantees that it will repeat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Branch By Abstraction</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/branch-by-abstraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/branch-by-abstraction/</guid>
      <description>The problem I want to write code that is consistently shared with the rest of the team, but I also want trunk based development.
What is branch by abstraction Paul Hammant a friend and mentor of mine, has two great articles explaining branch by abstraction here and here. The basic concept is pretty easy. Instead of having long lived branches in your version control system, you simply create an abstraction that allows you to change the behavior with only a few minor changes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
