<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Charlton Austin</title>
    <link>https://charltonaustin.com/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Charlton Austin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 10:17:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charltonaustin.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maslow Hierarchy of An App</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/maslow-hierarchy-of-an-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 10:17:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/maslow-hierarchy-of-an-app/</guid>
      <description>https://www.cbinsights.com/research/maslows-hierarchy-of-needs-startups/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Points What Are They Good For</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/points-what-are-they-good-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 10:17:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/points-what-are-they-good-for/</guid>
      <description>Should story points be tied to time I often hear people say story point shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be tied to time. Instead they should be based on complexity. This can be for a variety of reason. Here for instance three reasons are cited.
Some tasks are difficult to estimate precisely.
If one developer estimates a project but another completes the task, the estimate becomes invalid. The time needed to complete a task will vary based on a developer’s level of experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bugs In Software</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/bugs-in-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/bugs-in-software/</guid>
      <description>The Architecture of Open Source Applications If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen or read The Architecture of Open Source Applications then you are missing out. Sure, it is a bit long. Also, each section is written by a different writer making it slightly inconsistent. But, there are gems throughout the book that make it worth the read.
One of the gems Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of one of the gems from the Berkeley DB section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Review Of Test Driven Development With Go</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-review-of-test-driven-development-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-review-of-test-driven-development-with-go/</guid>
      <description>In a previous blog entry I talk about my recent technical challenge with CoreOS. I enjoyed my interview there so much that I started doing some reading about Go. Here&amp;rsquo;s a second book that I read that I would like to write a review about. It&amp;rsquo;s called Test-Driven Development With Go written by Yigal Duppen. You can find it on leanpub and it costs $0-14.99. I was tempted when I came across it to pay for it, but I thought maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll give it a read before I pay the author (authors have to eat too).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Review Of An Introduction To Programming In Go</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-review-of-an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-review-of-an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had a chance to write some Go code for the first time in a few years as part of the interview process at CoreOS. The challenge was actually really fun, but so as not to ruin surprise I won&amp;rsquo;t be talking about what I did during the challenge. Suffice it to say that I had a great experience, and whether or not I get the job at CoreOS I definitely enjoyed the interview process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make it stick</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/make-it-stick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/make-it-stick/</guid>
      <description>The book Make It Stick is a brief review of the best methods for learning. The book starts out by giving a brief overview of how teachers have tried to teach in the past and then turns to evidence based methods backed by science today. There is some repetition in content, but I immediately tried to implement the practices in the book and found that it dramatically changed the way that I read and study.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
