<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>golang on Charlton Austin</title>
    <link>https://charltonaustin.com/tags/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in golang on Charlton Austin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 09:03:54 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charltonaustin.com/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sudoku Using Go Lang</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/sudoku-using-go-lang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/sudoku-using-go-lang/</guid>
      <description>Algorithms A friend of mine recently started looking for work and we were talking about the interview process. She brought up the fact that often coding every day as a professional looks nothing like the toy problems in interviews. This got me thinking about a surprise question that I had during an interview. I was asked to create a Sudoku solver. At the time I was pretty vexed. I&amp;rsquo;ve never worked as a game programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating A Web Api With Golang</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/creating-a-web-api-with-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/creating-a-web-api-with-golang/</guid>
      <description>I had a chance for the first time in a while to write some Go. I was writing a simple web API that allowed a user to login with JWT. This blog post is going to be about some of the challenges I faced along the way. I also want to give some shout outs to other blogs that helped me get it written.
The IDE First let&amp;rsquo;s start with the IDE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Review Of An Introduction To Programming In Go</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-review-of-an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-review-of-an-introduction-to-programming-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had a chance to write some Go code for the first time in a few years as part of the interview process at CoreOS. The challenge was actually really fun, but so as not to ruin surprise I won&amp;rsquo;t be talking about what I did during the challenge. Suffice it to say that I had a great experience, and whether or not I get the job at CoreOS I definitely enjoyed the interview process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
