<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>management on Charlton Austin</title>
    <link>https://charltonaustin.com/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in management on Charlton Austin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charltonaustin.com/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Commander&#39;s Intent in Distributed Teams</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/commanders-intent-in-distributed-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/commanders-intent-in-distributed-teams/</guid>
      <description>Commander&amp;rsquo;s intent In today&amp;rsquo;s world, distributed teams are becoming more and more common. With remote work becoming the norm, the ability for a team to work effectively together relies on everyone understanding the goal and working towards it as hard as possible. In this context, commander&amp;rsquo;s intent can be a powerful tool for teams to take advantage of opportunities and achieve their goals. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the importance of commander&amp;rsquo;s intent in distributed teams, and how it can help smaller companies and startups to succeed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Time Zone Differences in Remote Teams</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/navigating-time-zone-differences-in-remote-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/navigating-time-zone-differences-in-remote-teams/</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s globalized world, remote teams are becoming increasingly common. However, with team members located in different time zones, scheduling meetings and collaborations can become more difficult. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some tips and strategies to help remote teams navigate time zone differences and work more effectively together, as well as some common pitfalls to avoid.
What doesn&amp;rsquo;t work: No meetings at all: While it may seem like avoiding meetings altogether would solve the time zone issue, it can actually limit communication and collaboration within the team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Lack of Team Cohesion in Remote Teams</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/overcoming-lack-of-cohesion-in-remote-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/overcoming-lack-of-cohesion-in-remote-environments/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As remote work has become increasingly popular, businesses face new challenges when it comes to fostering team cohesion. Without face-to-face interactions, building camaraderie and trust can be difficult. However, there are several strategies that can help remote teams overcome these obstacles and create an inclusive and effective work environment.
Encourage Teamwork through Remote Games and Relax Time One successful strategy for building team cohesion in remote teams is incorporating remote games and relaxation time during work hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication in Remote Start-Ups</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/communication-in-remote-start-ups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/communication-in-remote-start-ups/</guid>
      <description>Communication Challenges in a Remote Startup: Tips for Overcoming Them Remote work has become increasingly popular in recent years, but it comes with its own unique set of challenges One of the biggest hurdles that remote startups face is communication In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some of the common communication challenges in a remote startup and provide tips for overcoming them.
1. Work on Communication Skills Communication is always more difficult in a remote environment However, there are things you can do to combat this While many people may suggest adding more meetings, this can actually kill productivity Instead, focus on making sure your team knows and learns strong communication skills This means respecting other people&amp;rsquo;s opinions, avoiding arguments, and taking on disagreements in a tactful manner This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should hide disagreements, but rather that you should approach them constructively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Guide to Productive Weekly One-on-One Meetings with Employees</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-weekly-one-on-one-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/a-weekly-one-on-one-checklist/</guid>
      <description>As a manager, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to have regular one-on-one meetings with your direct reports. These meetings allow you to stay connected with your employees, address their concerns, and give them the feedback they need to grow professionally. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll share a simple checklist to help you have effective weekly check-ins with your employees.
The Checklist: How was last week? Is there anything I need to know about that I don&amp;rsquo;t know about?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure is Inevitable</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/failure-is-inevitable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/failure-is-inevitable/</guid>
      <description>Failure is Inevitable Dealing with failure is an inevitable part of life, especially when you&amp;rsquo;re an entrepreneur. While it can be tempting to try to avoid failure at all costs, the truth is that failure is an essential part of the learning process. By acknowledging our failures and learning from them, we can become better, more successful versions of ourselves.
How to learn from it In order to learn from failure, there are three things that we must do:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bugs In Software</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/bugs-in-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/bugs-in-software/</guid>
      <description>The Architecture of Open Source Applications If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen or read The Architecture of Open Source Applications then you are missing out. Sure, it is a bit long. Also, each section is written by a different writer making it slightly inconsistent. But, there are gems throughout the book that make it worth the read.
One of the gems Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of one of the gems from the Berkeley DB section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance Of History</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/the-importance-of-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/the-importance-of-history/</guid>
      <description>History, what is it good for? When I interview someone I often ask, &amp;ldquo;Where did object oriented programming (OOP) come from?&amp;rdquo; There generally isn&amp;rsquo;t a right or wrong answer to this in the interview. You can go look up whether a particular answer is consistent with what&amp;rsquo;s on the internet. However you could give several answers that would all be right. You might say, &amp;ldquo;it was pioneered in Sketchpad.&amp;rdquo; Or you might say, &amp;ldquo;it came out of the atom in LISP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blameless Postmortems</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/blameless-postmortems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/blameless-postmortems/</guid>
      <description>Subject Why should we have blameless postmortems?
Context I recently read a blog post about blameless postmortems from Etsy. In it there was a simple question about why software engineers shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be punished:
Why shouldn’t they be punished or reprimanded? Because an engineer who thinks they’re going to be reprimanded are disincentivized to give the details necessary to get an understanding of the mechanism, pathology, and operation of the failure. This lack of understanding of how the accident occurred all but guarantees that it will repeat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Your Team</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/developing-your-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 09:03:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/developing-your-team/</guid>
      <description>The problem You want to encourage people on your team to be the best they can be.
Some thoughts I&amp;rsquo;m a big reader. So the first thing I did when I came across this problem was to start a search on Amazon. Admittedly I only read a few books. I&amp;rsquo;m no guru. I don&amp;rsquo;t even think I&amp;rsquo;m that experienced. But I do think I&amp;rsquo;ve found a few strategies that have worked so far.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
