<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on Charlton Austin</title>
    <link>https://charltonaustin.com/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on Charlton Austin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charltonaustin.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why you should read the fine print</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/2023_05_16_why_you_should_always_read_the_fine_print/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/2023_05_16_why_you_should_always_read_the_fine_print/</guid>
      <description>I was driving a truck in Iraq when the first IED exploded. I remember seeing the vehicle in front of me burst into flames and feeling the heat come through the steering wheel. My world went quiet, and everything felt distant like I was seeing the world through a fishbowl.
The next thing I knew, someone was screaming at me to drive. I snapped out of my daze and hit the gas pedal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Be an Empathetic Leader: Strategies for Effective Leadership</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/being-an-empathetic-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/being-an-empathetic-leader/</guid>
      <description>Empathy is a critical skill for any leader who wants to build a successful and sustainable organization. It enables leaders to connect with their employees on a personal level, understand their needs and concerns, and create a positive work environment that fosters engagement and productivity. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some practical strategies for becoming a more empathetic leader. In the Marine Corps I was always taught to know your Marines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure is Inevitable</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/failure-is-inevitable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/failure-is-inevitable/</guid>
      <description>Failure is Inevitable Dealing with failure is an inevitable part of life, especially when you&amp;rsquo;re an entrepreneur. While it can be tempting to try to avoid failure at all costs, the truth is that failure is an essential part of the learning process. By acknowledging our failures and learning from them, we can become better, more successful versions of ourselves.
How to learn from it In order to learn from failure, there are three things that we must do:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
