<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>communication on Charlton Austin</title>
    <link>https://charltonaustin.com/tags/communication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in communication on Charlton Austin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://charltonaustin.com/tags/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming Lack of Team Cohesion in Remote Teams</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/overcoming-lack-of-cohesion-in-remote-environments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/overcoming-lack-of-cohesion-in-remote-environments/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As remote work has become increasingly popular, businesses face new challenges when it comes to fostering team cohesion. Without face-to-face interactions, building camaraderie and trust can be difficult. However, there are several strategies that can help remote teams overcome these obstacles and create an inclusive and effective work environment.
Encourage Teamwork through Remote Games and Relax Time One successful strategy for building team cohesion in remote teams is incorporating remote games and relaxation time during work hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communication in Remote Start-Ups</title>
      <link>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/communication-in-remote-start-ups/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://charltonaustin.com/posts/communication-in-remote-start-ups/</guid>
      <description>Communication Challenges in a Remote Startup: Tips for Overcoming Them Remote work has become increasingly popular in recent years, but it comes with its own unique set of challenges One of the biggest hurdles that remote startups face is communication In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore some of the common communication challenges in a remote startup and provide tips for overcoming them.
1. Work on Communication Skills Communication is always more difficult in a remote environment However, there are things you can do to combat this While many people may suggest adding more meetings, this can actually kill productivity Instead, focus on making sure your team knows and learns strong communication skills This means respecting other people&amp;rsquo;s opinions, avoiding arguments, and taking on disagreements in a tactful manner This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should hide disagreements, but rather that you should approach them constructively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
